# 哈喽大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 今天跟大家分享一下
Today I'd like to share with you some tips.
# 怎么样子用这种家庭小灶的锅
How to use a small family stove and wok like this
# 就是让它炒出酒店的那种猛火的感觉
Making it feel like a professional stove in restaurant kitchen.
# 就是很多粉丝在问说有的菜我们的教学他做不了
A lot of fans are complaining that they can't reproduce the dish in my recipe videos.
# 说家庭这个灶火太小了
Said their family stove was too small.
# 比如说爆炒一些的东西
Like some stir-fry dishes.
# 这个火小了之后就炒不起来
It won't cook properly without high heat.
# 然后今天跟大家分享一下
And today I'm going to share some tips with you.
# 怎么样在家庭里面把这个家庭小灶这个火把它用到极致
How to use this small family wok to the extreme.
# 今天我用了这个大白菜大家都知道
I used this Chinese cabbage today. As you know...
# 这个大白菜炒起很容易出水是不是
This Chinese cabbage is very watery, right?
# 炒起水咋咋的
It's watery if done wrong.
# 如果说我们的家庭小灶的火太小了
If use small family stove, the heat is too weak.
# 这个大白菜下到锅里面炒
Sometime once the cabbage is in the wok.
# 不叫做炒叫做煮菜
It becomes boiled instead of stir fried.
# 我们这个大白菜用手撕出来会更好一些
This cabbage is better if we tear it out by hand.
# 如果你不用手撕
If you don't use your hands.
# 最好的话用这种不锈钢刀
Use stainless steel knife.
# 最好就不要用那种铁刀来切
It's better not to cut with iron knives.
# 铁刀切了之后有股铁腥味 锈味
When you cut it with an iron knife, it smells like rust.
# 我们撕白菜的时候这里面其实有的菜(叶)它有筋在里面
When we tear the cabbage, some of it actually has thick fibres in it.
# 这就是白菜（叶）里面的筋
This is the fibre inside the cabbage.
# 如果你的牙口不好 吃起来还要塞牙 咬不动
If you've got bad teeth, you may find it hard to chew.
# 今天我用这个 用这个灶来模仿我们的家庭小灶
Today I'm using this stove to mimic our family stove.
# 虽然这个灶火力也很猛
It's a powerful stove, though.
# 我就把它开小一点
So I'll just turn it down quite a bit.
# 就是仿照一下家庭小灶那种小火慢慢烧的感觉
To mimic a slow-burning family stove.
# 现在我们这个火已经点起来了 就是比较小
Now we've got this fire going, it's kind of small.
# 大家可以看得到一点点（火）
You barely see the fire.
# 然后用这个铁锅放在上面烧
And then put this carbon steel wok on top of it.
# 我们第一步就是先把这个锅
Our first step is to get this wok hot.
# 烧到它不变味 不发红
Heat it as much as possible but don't let it burn or turn red.
# 尽可能把它烧烫一点
Get it as hot as possible.
# 而且这个边也要把它烧到
And the side should also be heated.
# 慢慢烧反正小火嘛
Take your time. It's low flame anyway.
# 但是有一点就是不建议大家用那个不粘锅去这么烧
But one thing we don't recommend is using non-stick pan to cook like this.
# 不粘锅这么一烧就坏了
Non-stick pans' coating will break.
# 好 我们的铁锅已经烧的差不多了开始放油
Okay, the temperature is almost there, and we're adding oil to the wok.
# 如果我们要提升锅里面的温度
If we want to raise the temperature during frying.
# 油的量多少也很关键
The amount of oil is also critical.
# 你看这个油一放下去马上就冒烟了
Look at the oil, it's going to smoke as soon as you put it down.
# 如果说锅不热的话放下去油就不会冒烟
If the pan is not hot, the oil won't smoke.
# 现在直接放下去炒
Now, just put cabbage in and fry it.
# 大家听到这个响声没有
Did you hear that sound?
# 你看这就是家里的炒法
You see, this is how it's done at home.
# 大家看一下
Take a look, everyone.
# 我们这个菜都炒出了锅气来了
We got wok hei here.
# 而且有种要糊不糊的
And it's caramelized, almost burnt.
# 要的就是这种感觉
That's the feeling.
# 如果火大两下就炒糊了
If you turn up the heat again, it'll burn.
# 你看这个就是爆炒的感觉啊
Look at this. It's like proper stir frying.
# 我依然用的小火（炒）
This is still low heat.
# 还有我们炒青菜不要太早放盐
And we don't put salt in too early when dealing with vegetables.
# 放完盐下去也会马上出水
If you put salt in it, the water will come right out.
# 反正我们这个菜一出水就不好吃了
It's not good once the water is out during frying.
# 我们就干炒 千万不要加水炒这种大白菜
We'll just dry stir-fry it. Never add water to this cabbage.
# 你看现在好没好 好了
This is looking good now. Yes.
# 你看
Look.
# 好 我们现在放盐
Okay, we'll put the salt in now.
# 最后一下我们把盐放下去
Let's put the salt in at the last step.
# 然后再翻炒几下
And then toss a few times.
# 那个盐炒化了就可以了
Just let the salt dissolve.
# 我们现在就出锅 出锅之前我们看一下
We're going to take it out of the wok right now, but before we do, let's take a look at it.
# 出锅之前我们看一下
Let's take a look before we serve it.
# 在锅底是一点水都没有
There's no water at all at the bottom of the wok.
# 看到没
You see?
# 真的是没有汤汁
There's really no water.
# 我们这个（炒）出来之后是一点汤都没有
There's no water at all after cook.
# 然后我们可以看一下这个菜
Then we can look at the dish.
# 菜里面也是一点水都没有
There's no water in the dish either.
# 而且有一种爆炒的感觉
And there's stir fried feel to it.
# 大家可以看一下
You can see it.
# 可以看一下这里还有一点点
You can see there's a little bit here...
# 一点要糊不糊的那种感觉是不是 嗯
The caramelized bits.
# 就是焦香焦香的那种感觉
You know, the toasty smell.
# 所以我们很多粉丝他说在家里面炒菜
So many of you guys saying when you do it at home.
# 小火小灶根本达不到说像酒店的那种效果
It's not even close to a restaurant stove.
# 其实不是的 是我们没有把这个锅用好
Actually it's because you are not using heat up the wok properly.
# 你闻闻看
You smell it.
# 有点香
It smells good.
# 一是你的油香 二是锅烧烫了下去几下就好了
Your oil smells good, and the wok is hot, so it's easy to make it good.
# 就是有些粉丝他说他屋头
Some fans said they couldn't replicate the dish at home.
# 拿那种小锅炒 炒不出这样的效果
Saying they can't make proper stir fry in a small frying wok like this.
# 其实有时候炒菜 火大火小是有一点影响
In fact, although the heat does have some effect,
# 但是家里一样的可以炒得出这种感觉来
you can still get similar result despite the stove.
# 再加上放盐那里也有关系啊 嗯
And also the salt has something to do with it, too.
# 多早把盐放下去它（菜里面）的水就出来了
Adding salt too early will ruin the dish, the water will come out.
# 所以我们记住了炒青菜一定要最后放盐这就是是为什么
That's why we need to make sure to always add salt at the end of the frying process.
# 又香
Fragrant!
# 又甜又脆
Sweet and crunchy.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个味道是不一样
The taste is so different.
# 是吧 我们如果说火小了锅都没烧热 菜下去慢慢煮煮出来
Right? Without properly heating up the wok, the vegetables won't cook quickly and will become boiled instead.
# 不香不说还有一股水臭味
It won't caramelize, and will taste watery.
# 还有我们这个锅也很有讲究
And the wok is also very important.
# 我们越小的火啊
The smaller the flame,
# 在家庭小灶里面越小的火
The smaller the fire in home.
# 就要用越厚的那个铁锅
The thicker the wok should be.
# 因为为什么要用越厚的呢而不是用越薄的
Why use the thicker ones instead of the thinner ones?
# 因为越厚的铁锅它可以吸收更多的热量在里面保存起来
Because thicker woks retain heat better.
# 你这个菜一下去炒的时候
When you fry the dish.
# 这个热量不会一下子就没有了它还有后续（温度）
This heat doesn't go away all at once so the wok remains relatively hot.
# 立马烧不热 但是冷又很快冷不了
It will take longer to heat up, but it doesn't lose heat as fast
# 哦 对对对
Oh, yeah.
# 反正就是说我们这个锅家庭小灶
Anyway, that means if you want to choose a wok for home stove.
# 选铁锅一定要选越厚的越好
The thicker the pot, the better.
# 他可以储存（更多的）热量
It retains more heat.
# 这个问题也困扰了粉丝很多年
It's a question that has troubled our fans for years.
# 今天可能我说的不是很直观
Maybe you still don't understand after today's demo.
# 如果你们想看它的原理的话
If you want to see how it works and the difference.
# 就在评论里面说想看
Just leave your comments down below.
# 然后我下一期拍一期就更加直观的给大家看一下
Maybe I'll shoot another video to show you more visually.
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里
All right, that's it for this video.
# 拜拜
Bye-bye